<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[My digital scrapbook]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[My digital scrapbook]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/kazarnowicz/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 13:28:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/kazarnowicz/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Chinese citizens now have a score based on how well we live, and mine sucks]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>All Chinese citizens now have a score based on how well we live, and mine sucks</h1><p>Chinese citizens share just as many cat photos and memes online as people do anywhere else. But in the past few weeks I began to notice a mysterious new trend. Numbers were popping up on my social media feeds as my friends and strangers on Weibo and WeChat began to share their 芝麻信用分, or "Sesame Credit scores."</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/6c33b45c97bbde652f7bd3bb2e0fbd001f18a01e.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://qz.com/519737/all-chinese-citizens-now-have-a-score-based-on-how-well-we-live-and-mine-sucks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">be8ada3e-7346-489d-b942-cef3bf24970b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 13:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Hi there. I've been living in China for four months and had no idea this system existed. I work with people who are self-professed 'members of the party' and at first this was terrifying to me because every time I logged on to my VPN in order to tunnel under The Great Firewall of China I thought I was five minutes away from being dragged into the back of a van for processing. I've since become much more relaxed as it seems that the Chinese have a flexible attitude towards the law. If you are in need of hard-to-get paperwork, pay someone at the office to expedite the process. If you're on the road and you're in a hurry but the red light is just too inconvenient, roll right on through. If you need access to Facebook for marketing purposes because your company's operations depend on it, use a VPN. Pull out a cigarette in front of a 'no smoking' sign and the staff will offer a lighter.   This flexibility towards the law seems to stand in contradiction to the Sesame Credit system which. to my mind, is a way of formalising 'guanxi' (goo-an-she), commonly approximated as 'face' in the English language (as in 'saving face'). Guanxi is a kind of social currency that has existed informally for thousands of years. Treat all of your colleagues to an elaborate meal or agree to work overtime for no extra pay and you will earn guanxi. Keep accumulating guanxi and you will have the right to ask a favour of your superiors, and you may even be promoted. Since there is already a social sense of togetherness, guanxi is usually accumulated through acts that adhere to the communist party's approved behavioural patterns. The Chinese already think of themselves as one people and question the validity of an action that is too individualistic. In many ways the Sesame Credit system has been in operation for a long time, but this conscious process of formalisation will give total control of every aspect of the country's governance to a very small minority who will no doubt choose to stamp out those cheeky rule-benders.  I miss drugs ;_;﻿</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/kazarnowicz/hi-there-ive-been-living-in-china-for-four-months-and-had/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">00908de3-9388-4940-a9de-7c167def17cd</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Propaganda Games: Sesame Credit - The True Danger of Gamification - Extra Credits]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Propaganda Games: Sesame Credit - The True Danger of Gamification - Extra Credits</h1><p>This is a good overview of the dangers of a gamified citizen score system (even if there are some factual errors about Sesame)</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/eecfe71bc053f4c85e5195547c4df95860602332.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lHcTKWiZ8sI&amp;feature=youtu.be</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ef8924eb-7967-4f12-bbc8-f8de95e54fd2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:06:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[China 'social credit': Beijing sets up huge system - BBC News]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>China 'social credit': Beijing sets up huge system - BBC News</h1><p>In most countries, the existence of a credit system isn't controversial. Past financial information is used to predict whether individuals will pay their mortgages or credit card bill in the future. But China is taking the whole concept a few steps further.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/c84cb4285a9b4404f68d3ada718da99193c6dddb.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-34592186</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e3d1247f-ef52-4020-b934-04d8256c2088</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 11:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>